# 你看 這個豬
Look! This pig,
# 是昨天我們餵了它很好那個酒糟給它(註︰翻譯法似奇怪，但是因為他中間改了句式)
is the one we've...we've fed it with a lot of distiller grains.
# 你看 現在都 軟趴趴了吧
Look! It's now, drunk as a boiled owl.
# 那麼兇
So fierce!
# 那天 咬我
That day, you bit me!
# 這只公豬
This boar,
# 你看這公的太大了 等下吃不完 我們搞條小的
Look! This boar is too large, we might not be able to finish it. Let's get a small one.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 我剛 剛把那個刀磿利了
I, um, I've just sharpened the, well, the knife.
# 得快的哦
It won't take long.
# 沒事 走
No worries! Let's go!
# 走
Go!
# 看你喝醉了 還那麼厲害
How can you still be that staunch when you're drunk?
# 好 好 好兇啊
So, so, so fierce!
# 等下我們兩個人把它枱下去
Let's take it down there together.
# 剛剛抬了一隻一下去哦 現在再抬一隻
We've just taken one down there. Here's another one.
# 搞兩隻
We'll have two.
# 曾經的雞 (註︰非字幕)
The chicken in the past
# 叫兄弟也過來 一起 一起殺豬 (註︰這裡的「殺」是指整個屠宰過程)
I've asked my buddy to, to handle the pigs together.
# 等一下分豬肉
We'll then share the pork.
# 我來我來我來
I'm coming, I'm coming!
# 吶 你來 我去把那把刀拿上來
Na! You do it! I'm gonna fetch that knife.
# 來 使勁燙
C'mon! Scald it!
# 死豬不怕開水燙
It's dead. It's cares nothing.
# 放到那個臉盆裡面去 這個 毛不好褪
We'll put it into the basin. It's, It's hard to dehair.
# 豬頭也燙一下
Scald the head as well.
# 可以 可以拔了沒
Can, can we pluck it now?
# 好不好拔
Is it easy?
# 誒呀 可以啦
Eya! It's alright now.
# 現在已經把它破開啦
We've cut it open now.
# 明天再搞
Let's continue tomorrow.
# 今天太晚啦
It's too late today.
# 先把它放好 放起來
Let's place it, place it well.
# 大家好 今天我檢點那個柴火 來烤一下那個豬排
Hi everyone! I've picked some, some twigs, to grill, grill the ribs.
# 先拍點生薑下去
Smash some ginger first.
# 老薑
Old ginger
# 這個排骨要腌一下
The ribs need to be marinated for a while.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 再加點料酒
And some cooking wine too.
# 醬油
Soy sauce
# 這個要加油 不加油的話等一下 等一下會乾巴巴的
It needs some oil. Otherwise it would be, it would be very dry.
# 搞點辣椒粉
Get some chili powder.
# 辣椒粉才是最好吃的
The best seasoning is nothing but chili powder.
# 腌它半個小時左右
Marinate it for about half an hour.
# 豬排
Ribs!
# 搞一根棍子
Let me get a stick,
# 等下可以戳兩下
so that I can pierce the ribs.
# 好 可以
Alright! It's good enough.
# 開始
Let's start!
# 搞個凳子坐一下
Let me get a stool.
# 這樣可以
Then I can sit here.
# 誒呀
Eya!
# 這個姿勢可以
A good posture.
# 剛好搞一根棍子把它插起來 (註︰這句很難完全譯過來，改一下字眼)
I got this stick to skewer it.
# 看 放下去先
Look! Put it here first.
# 這個 不好烤
It's hard to grill.
# 把它砍一下
Let me hack it,
# 把它砍成貼在那裡的 (註︰Chop有砍碎的意思，不合這裡，他事實上是在亂劈，所以用hack)
so that it can lie flat.
# 好 可以啦
Good! It's alright now.
# 現在就挺好啦
It's much better now.
# 來 掃一層
Alright! Put on a layer.
# 划一下這個肉
Let me scratch the meat,
# 容易熟一點
to shorten the grilling time.
# 加點這個孜然粉
Put some, some cumin powder.
# 更美味呦
It tastes much better.
# 你看 這就烤好了哦
Look! It's done.
# 全部狗都圍過來啦
The dogs are all coming around me.
# 嗯
Um!
# 味道很不錯哦
It tastes really not bad.
# 這裡還有骨頭
Here's still a piece of bone.
# 這狗口水都流出來了
The dogs are already drooling.
# 給這個母狗吃
It's for the mother.
# 這些全部看我
They're all watching me.
# 怎麼一點都不辣 那辣椒肯定是假的
Why isn't it even a bit spicy. The chili must be fake.
# 下次多放一點辣椒粉
I'll put more chili powder next time.
# 這個烤的[SIC]很香
It smells really good!
# 下次我們多烤一點
Let's make more next time.
# 還要做點臘肉
We need to make some cured pork too.
# 這兩天我們把那個豬啊 搞點臘肉出來
We'll make some cured pork, from the pig, in a couple of days.
# 這味道不錯
It tastes not bad.
# 這個
Here,
# 有點焦焦的
it's a bit blackened.
# 特別好吃
It's exceptionally good.
# 前兩天那小狗生啦 現在豬又生啦
The dog gave birth a couple of days ago. And now it's the turn of the pig.
# 生了一大堆
Here's a whole bunch of them,
# 11條哦
eleven pigs.
# 生了好小
They're really small.
# 又生了那麼多
It gave birth to so many again.
# 你看 這個公豬
Look! The boar,
# 公豬在守著哦 不要我過去喲
the boar is on guard. It's not letting me pass through.
# 這個小豬
The piglets,
# 好可愛呀
are so cute.
# 不敢去抓 這公的在這裡
I dare not catch them. The boar is here.
# 等我一去抓的話 它又要拱我
It would attack me again if I attempt to catch them.
# 差點踩死那個小的
It almost stepped on the small one.
# 你不要去看它哦 看它它就覺得
Don't look at it. It might think...
# 吃奶啦 吃奶啦 快點
Suck the milk! Suck the milk! C'mon!
# 有一條好小的 它這裡
There's a very small one. It's here.
# 扔一點那個菜葉子給它
Let me throw them some veggie leaves.
# 嗯 吃點菜葉子
Um! Have some veggie leaves!
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 我們不能去打擾它啦
We can't disturb it anymore.
# 等一下它發飆啦
It would go mad otherwise.